♪♪～
♪ Blooming wildflower ♪
（いのり）
♪♪「咲いた野の花よ」
♪ I beg you, please tell me ♪
（いのり）♪♪「ああ　どうか
おしえておくれ」
♪♪「人は何故　傷つけあって」
♪ Why do people fight and hurt each other? ♪
♪♪「争うのでしょう」
♪ Valiantly blooming flower ♪
♪♪「りんと咲く花よ」
♪ What can you see from your field? ♪
♪♪「そこから何が見える」
♪♪「人は何故…」
♪ Why can't people forgive each other? ♪
[無線]（涯）鍵は手に入れたか？
うん。
Have you secured the key?
Yeah.
Good work. I'll guide you out.
[無線]（涯）よくやった　誘導する。→
３０秒で合流する。
We'll meet up in thirty seconds.
♪♪「雨が過ぎて夏は　青を移した」
♪ The rain passed, and summer took on blue hues ♪
♪ All alone now ♪
♪♪「一つになって」
♪ You trembled before me ♪
♪♪「小さく揺れた私の前で」
♪ Without saying a word ♪
♪♪「何も言わずに」
ハァ　ハァ…。　ハッ！
うっ…。
♪ When your friends wilt around you ♪
♪♪「枯れていく友に」
♪ What do you think? ♪
♪♪「おまえは何を思う」
♪ With your leaves unable to speak, ♪
♪♪「ことばを持たぬ　その葉で…」
Please, Funell. Get this to Gai.
お願い　ふゅーねる。
これを涯に。
♪ how do you convey love? ♪
♪♪～
♪ Summer's sun clouded over, the wind streamed by ♪
I'll cover you!
♪ The two overlapped ♪
（綾瀬）「カバーするわ。
あなたは　早く　それを涯に！」
You get that to Gai, quick!
Funell...
♪ The two overlapped ♪
ふゅーねる！
♪♪～
♪ I shall sing the proof that you lived ♪
（綾瀬）「しまった！」
Oh, crap!
♪♪～
♪ For the sake of those who have no names ♪
あーっ！！
♪♪～
outbreak
（集）ふあー。
（祭）おはよう　集。→
Morning, Shu!
That was a major yawn. What's the deal?
どうしたの？　すごい　あくび。
（集）うん…　ちょっとね。
Yeah, well...
（祭）ネットでも　うろついてたの？それとも　ゲームとか？
Were you surfing the net or something?
Or playing a game?
あっ　読書？
（集）うん…　まあ　そんなとこ。
Reading?
Something like that, I guess...
Huh. Fine, then.
ふーん。　なら　いいけどさ。
"Danger"
（集）何か多いね　今日。
（祭）ニュース　見てないの？
Lots of them out today, huh?
Didn't you see the news?
昨日　テロとか
何かあったらしいよ　お台場。
Apparently there was some terrorist
attack or something yesterday,
in Odaiba... well, no, I guess that
area's called "Ward 24" now.
じゃなくて　今は　２４区だっけ。
ふーん。
≪（颯太）おい　集！
Hey, Shu!
Oh, sorry, I'm not done with
that video for the competition yet.
ああ　ごめん。　コンクール用のビデオクリップ
まだ　できてないんだ。
（颯太）べ…　別に催促じゃねえよ。
じゃあ　何の用？
I didn't come to harp on you about it...
What did you want, then?
I'll get it done by the deadline, don't worry.
期限には間に合わすから
心配しないで。
Now look, Shu, I...
（颯太）あのな　集！　俺は…。
（谷尋）いいじゃんか　颯太。
Eh, let it go, Souta.
He says he can do it, after all.
やれるってんだし。
じゃ　頼んだぜ。
Okay, we're counting on you!
かわいそう　颯太君。
I feel bad for Souta.
何で？　これでも　頑張って
空気読んでるつもりなんだけど。
Why? I think I'm working really
hard to be socially perceptive here.
読めてないよ。
You're not succeeding.
そうかな。
鈍過ぎだよ。
Oh...
You're way too dense.
Rise!
≪（生徒）起立！
《僕が鈍い？》
I'm "dense"?
Maybe it's true that my mind works
out of step with everyone else's.
《みんなと　感覚が　ずれてるって
いうなら　そうかもしれない》
It's just that I don't know
what to say to other people.
《僕には分からないだけだ。
みんなと何を話したらいいのか》
So I hide my nervousness and
go along with what they say;
《だから　内心　焦りながら
話を合わせて→
友達風のものを増やして
生きてきた》
that's how I've made
the quasi-friendships in my life.
《日本は今
独立風の主権で運営している》
Right now Japan operates as
a"quasi-independent" nation.
That's what my mom says.
《母さんは　そう言う》
"Was a Biological Weapon Used!?"
"Anarchy Reigns"
Ten years ago, the Apocalypse Virus
pandemic wreaked havoc on this country,
《１０年前　アポカリプスウイルスのパンデミックで→
"Panic in Roppongi"
Ten years ago, the Apocalypse Virus
pandemic wreaked havoc on this country,
この国は　めちゃくちゃになって》
and we relied on an unbelievable amount
of help from many other countries...
《大勢の　よその国に
とんでもなく　お世話になって》
And we're still dependent on them even now...
《今でも　お世話になりっ放しで→
Japan's foundations are just barely holding.
日本は　ようやく
屋台骨を支えている》
《いろんな事実が
僕らに伝えてくる》
We're informed of various facts:
"We can't leave this to you."
《「君たちには任せておけない」》
"You don't have the power to protect
the people who are important to you."
《「君たちには
大切な人を守る能力がない」》
But... shouldn't we do better than that?
《でも　それでいいのかな？》
《僕にも　もっと
やれること　ないのかな…》
Isn't there something more I, personally, can do?
"Blockade Zone"
♪ Blooming wildflower ♪
♪♪「咲いた野の花よ」→
♪ I beg you, please tell me ♪
♪♪「ああ　どうか
おしえておくれ」
♪♪「人は何故　傷つけあって」
♪ Why do people fight and hurt each other? ♪
♪♪「争うのでしょう」
♪ Valiantly blooming flower ♪
♪♪「りんと咲く花よ」
♪ What... ♪
♪♪「そ…」
（缶を蹴る音）
ぐっ…　うわー！
あの…　違くて！
そんなつもり　全然なくって！
Um, you've got the wrong idea!
I totally didn't want to...!
Hey, are you...?!
君　もしかして…。
（起動音）
ま…　まだ途中なんだよ！
It's... It's not done yet!
It's a view of my hometown, and...
僕の　古里の景色…。
奇麗。
It's pretty.
えー？
Huh?
（おなかの鳴る音）
あっ。
Um, would you like a rice ball?
あの…　おにぎり食べる？
♪ London Bridge is falling down,
falling down, falling down. ♪
♪♪「ロンドン橋　落ちた
落ちた　落ちた」
あの…　いのりさんだよね？
♪♪「マイ　フェア　レディー」
- ♪ London Bridge is falling down, my fair lady. ♪
- Um, you're Inori, aren't you?
The Egoist vocalist?
ＥＧＯＩＳＴのボーカルの。
♪♪「ロンドン橋　落ちた　落ちた」
♪ London Bridge is falling down, ♪
- ♪ falling down, falling down. ♪
それで　何で　ここに？　っていうかどうして　そんなケガを？
- So, what are you doing here?
- ♪ falling down, falling down. ♪
No, more importantly, why are you so hurt?
この子を涯に届けるの。
えっ？
We have to get this to Gai.
取って。
Take this.
あ…。
取って。
Take this, er...
えーと…。
集！　桜満　集！
Shu! Shu Ouma!
やれば　できるかもしれない。
You might be able to do it if you try.
But you'll never be able to if you don't.
でも
やらないと　絶対に　できない。
桜満　集は臆病な人？
Shu Ouma... are you a coward?
Huh?
あれ…　何だ？　今の…。
What was that?
えっ！
ふゅーねる。
Funell.
いのりさん！
Inori!
Whoa, there.
（グエン）おっと。
うっ！
（グエン）学生か？
ハッ！
You're a student?
Y-Yes, Sir!
は…　はい！　あの…　その子
ケガをしてるんです。　できれば…。
Um, that girl is hurt. Please don't treat her...
（グエン）この女は犯罪者だ。
This woman is a criminal.
かばうなら
君も同罪として　浄化処分するぞ。
If you shield her, we'll purge
you too, as her accomplice.
わあっ…。　ハッ！
フン。　データ照合の結果は？
What does the data check show?
She's definitely a member of
the Funeral Parlor in Roppongi.
（兵士）六本木の「葬儀社」の一員に
間違いありません。
フン。　テロリスト風情が！
Little terrorist scum!
あっ…！
連行しろ。
（兵士たち）はっ。
Bring her in.
Yes, Sir!
こんな俺でいいのか…？
Shouldn't I be better than this?
《情けないことに
暴力の危険から解放されて→
I felt... a little relieved, because
I wasn't in danger of violence anymore.
少し　ほっとしていた》
That's how pathetic I am.
《その程度だ　僕は》
When you get right down to it,
she was way out of my league.
《しょせん　彼女の相手をできる
格じゃなかった》
Take this.
《取って》
《取りたかった》
I wanted to take it.
I wanted to get close to her, and touch her hand!
《あの子に近づいて
手を触れたかったよ…》
《もう忘れよう。
しばらく休めば　心が回復する》
Forget about it, Shu. Rest a while,
and your heart will bounce back.
After that, just go back to your normal self.
《そしたら
また　いつもの僕に戻ろう》
えっ？
We have to get this to Gai.
《この子を涯に届けるの》
Seriously? You're telling me to... go there?
マジか…。　そこに行けと…。
This might be my last chance to not hate myself.
《自分を嫌いにならない
最後のチャンスかもしれない！》
It had to be here, of all places...
よりによって　ここか…。
I'm told you've dispatched
a squadron to Roppongi?
（ヤン）六本木に　一個中隊を
派遣しているというが？
I believed it was necessary.
（茎道）必要と考えました。
That'll provoke unnecessary hostility.
（ヤン）いらぬ反感を買うぞ。
救済目的でなければ許可はできん。
I can't allow it if it's not for an aid mission.
（茎道）理解しております。
I understand that.
And? Exactly how dangerous
is this stolen Void Genom?
（高官）それで　いったい
どれほどの危険があるのかね？→
盗まれた　ヴォイド・ゲノムは。
It's...
（春夏）それは…。
（茎道）レベル３Ａの機密ですので。
That's level 3A classified information.
（ヤン）
だから　ＧＨＱ最高司令官たる→
And so you can't even tell me,
GHQ's Supreme Commander, is that it?
私にも明かせないと？
（茎道）申し訳ありませんが。→
I'm afraid so, Sir.
But please don't worry.
しかし　ご安心を。　犯人は　すでに
われわれ　アンチボディズが押さえ→
My Anti Bodies have already
apprehended the culprit,
and are searching for
the stolen genom as we speak.
現在は
盗まれたゲノムの捜索中です。
（グエン）まだ
しゃべる気にならんのかね？→
Still don't want to talk?
We've been granted the authority
to dispose of the diseased without warning.
われわれには　感染者を　無警告で
処分する権限が与えられている。→
If you don't tell us where you hid it,
隠し場所を言わねば→
この街の住民　全てを
浄化処分することになるぞ。
I'll just have to purge every
single resident of this neighborhood.
（グエン）クッ！　後悔するなよ。
Don't regret that later.
[無線]（グエン）全機に告ぐ。→
Attention all units.
作戦区画の全住民を
感染レベル４＋と認定！→
All residents in our operating area
are designated as Stage IV+ infected.
I hereby authorize infection control measures!
防疫行動を許可する！
（副官）あの娘の扱いは？
What shall we do with the girl?
戦闘開始後に　外で始末しろ。
After we commence hostilities,
get rid of her outside.
ここ…？
Is this it?
≪（男）おい　お前！
Hey, you!
Y-Yes?
あ…　はい。
それ　炊けんの？
えっ　何ですか？
That cook?
Excuse me?
それ　飯　炊けんの？
えっ！？
That thing cook rice?
あ…　いや…。
Well, no, I don't think it does...
それは　ないと思いますけど
たぶん。
Leave it.
（男）置いてけよ。
いや！　無理なんです。
N-No, I can't do that!
You messin' with me? Just hand it over.
（男）お前　ナメてんの？
いいから　それ　よこせよ。
I'm very sorry, but it doesn't belong to me!
ごめんなさい。　預かり物なんで…。あの子が必死に守ろうとしてた。
She worked so hard to protect it...
だから　すいません！
So... I'm sorry!
あぁ？
Greetings, my deceased fellows.
（涯）やあ　死人の諸君。
あぁ！？　「死人」だと？
（涯）ああ。→
"Deceased"?!
Yes. The current situation
doesn't allow for your survival.
今　この状況は
君たちの生存を許さない。
Therefore, you are all dead.
（涯）
故に　君たちは死んでいる。
あいつ　まさか…。
（男）涯！
Don't tell me he's...
...Gai!
（男）
勇気あんな　お前！　あぁ！？
You got some balls, kid.
♪♪～
Shit, who is this guy?!
≪（男）
くっそ！　何だ　こいつ！→
うわあっ！
♪♪～
（男）うっ　うわああっ！
あっ！　って…　あれ？
Wait, what?
That's Funell, right? Give it back!
（鶫）それ　ふゅーねるでしょ！？
返して！
あっ！
Shu Ouma, yes?
（涯）桜満　集か？
あれと一緒にいた女は　どうした？
What about the girl who was with that?
Well... I...
それは…　その…。
見捨てたのか。
You just abandoned her?
≪（爆発音）
Gai! The GHQ whitecoats are invading!
涯！　ＧＨＱの白服どもが
街に入り込んできてます！
≪（悲鳴）
Damn those bastards! They're firing
live rounds at anybody they see!
≪（アルゴ）
チキショー　あいつら！→
お構いなしに
実弾をばらまいていやがる！
鶫。　綾瀬たちは　どうしている？
Tsugumi, what's the word
on Ayase and the others?
綾姉たちは…。
They're...
Enemy incoming on our left!
左方に機影！
Beat it, you're in my way!
（綾瀬）「どいて！　邪魔よ！」
行け　集！
そいつを絶対に手放すな！
Go, Shu!
Don't you dare let go of that thing!
Protect it this time!
今度こそ　守ってみせろ！
♪♪～
《でも…　いったい　何が
できるつもりなんだろう　俺！》
But... what do I think I can do, exactly?
How many are we up against?
（綾瀬）「敵の数は？」
[無線]（鶫）んー　まだ不明！→
Not sure yet! More keep coming!
どんどん増えてるから！
（綾瀬）「しっかりしてよ！」
Get it together!
（綾瀬）あっ！
（綾瀬）「何するのよ！」
What do you think you're doing?!
（兵士たち）うわっ！
あっ！
♪♪～
いのりさん！
Inori!
Do something that's not
like you once in a while, Shu!
《たまには
自分らしくないことをやれ！》
うああっ！
うああああああ！！
（銃声）
あっ！
これは…！？
What...
うっ！
What is this?
何だ？
集…　お願い。　私を使って。
Shu, please...
...use me.
Take it this time, Shu.
（真名）
《取りなさい　集。　今度こそ》
《誰？》
（真名）《これは　力》→
Who are you?
This is power...
the guilty crown given shape
《人の心を紡いで形を成す
罪の王冠》
through the bond between hearts.
♪♪～
あっ！
何だ…？　これ。
What is this?
♪♪～
ぐっ！
あっ！
うあああああっ！！
（爆発音）
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…
ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…。
I'll never be loved by you again
♪♪～
Or needed by you again, either
And so here I am, all alone
What did you say that day?
Words that'll never be heard flutter in the air
Even though I know better,
I can't help making another
Hopeless wish today
Keep holding my hand tight and don't let go
Tell me you'll stay with me
Your hand in mine was warm and kind